HAN JEONG-U, TRAUMA CLEANER
SANG-GU'S OLDER BROTHER!
MAKE SURE THEY MEET!
You're such a fool.
I heard about Su-cheol.
When will you be here?
-No more of that.
-What?
I won't fight on the ring anymore.
Who says you have a choice?
Says me.
Are you out of your mind?
I'll pay off the debt,
but I won't fight anymore.
If you don't show up,
we'll all go down together.
That sounds even better.
ONE MESSAGE FROM UNCLE CHO SANG-GU
What?
He hasn't come home last few days.
Skipping work without notice?
He surely doesn't have
any sense of responsibility.
If I were his boss,
he'd be fired right away.
No!
We're in big trouble!
What was that?
Did something pass by?
Yes, it was your daughter
who's faster than Usain Bolt.
No, you can't!
Why? What's going on? What trouble?
Uncle--
What about him?
He ran away from home.
What?
DON'T WAIT FOR ME
I'M NOT COMING BACK
Let's find him.
Let's call the police.
He's not a kid.
They won't take it seriously.
Then what should we do?
Here's what.
We move on without him.
I can't accept that.
Why not?
When a family is missing,
we try to find them.
We can't just move on without him.
But how? Do you know anything about him?
No, I don't.
Do you?
Hey, how would I…?
No! I don't know anything.
PORORO BAND-AID FOR KIDS
LOOKING FOR MY MISSING UNCLE
LAST SEEN ON JUNE 7TH
FILTHY, LOUD, GOOD AT FIGHTING
CONTACT IF YOU'VE SEEN HIM
What?
Oh no.
Don't.
No!
MISSED CALLS: GEU-RU, NA-MU, MADAM
MADAM: YOUR NEPHEW IS LOOKING FOR YOU
Fuck.
Damn it.
Darn it.
Fuck, who cares?
Break time is over. Get back to work!
…between the eyes is flat.
It has a line of sharp barbs
on the body disc, extending to the tail.
The line falls gradually from the head…
-The front edge--
-Turn the darn lights on!
Hello, ma'am.
Your uncle
will be here.
Do you mean it?
If you lie, you'll go to hell
and eat 3,000 needles a day.
I read it in the book.
Yes, I mean it.
Are you my uncle's friend?
You can say that.
I think your uncle is here.
I won't have to
eat those needles, right?
Uncle!
What are you?
What the fuck?
-Out of the way!
-Leave him alone.
Uncle!
Geu-ru.
-Are you okay?
-I'm fine.
-What the heck is this?
-Uncle!
Don't be mad.
Your lady friend there isn't a bad person.
Were you really going to cut ties
and go off the grid?
I never knew Cho Sang-gu could
do such things.
I promised myself when I buried Su-cheol.
I won't fight again.
I'm sorry that he died.
However,
a promise is a promise.
What if I keep refusing?
I wasn't sure what to do
since Su-cheol died,
but luckily,
I've found your new Achilles' heel.
Taking him here was a test drive,
and I found the result very satisfactory.
He has nothing to do with me.
Is that why you got here so quickly?
His dad was my mortal enemy.
You'd actually do me a favor
if you hurt him.
Just keep your promise.
I don't want to go as low
as hurting a kid.
Fine. But you'll have to return
the house deed and the note
I signed last time.
No.
On the game night,
come here and take them yourself.
What are you doing?
Let's go home now.
Gosh.
Where is he?
Geu-ru!
Where have you been?
I've found Uncle.
Gosh, what the heck?
You're his guardian.
How can you go MIA for days?
What kind of guardian are you?
You know what a guardian means?
You're supposed to protect
and take care of Geu-ru. Get it?
Gosh.
Everyone is responsible
for their own life.
Looking out for someone?
There's no such thing.
Darn it.
Because you're all he's got.
For Geu-ru, you are
the only family he has.
LOOKING FOR MY MISSING UNCLE
This is a violation of my image rights!
There are better photos than this.
I watered the plant while you were gone.
I'm glad you're home.
Geu-ru.
Yes?
This isn't my home.
And I'm not your family either.
So if I ever disappear again,
never go looking for me.
Don't wander around alone.
If strangers try to take you away again,
call Na-mu or the cop friend immediately.
Got it?
Won't you come and get me, Uncle?
No.
Never.
Bring everyone.
Let's up the ante.
That's right.
We should go all in this time.
PLEDGE
NAME: CHO SANG-GU
MOVE TO HEAVEN
Are you really going?
Yes, I am.
Do you have to? Without your dad?
Yes, I do.
Then, let's go tomorrow with me.
No, I need to go today.
Then take your uncle with you.
I can't.
I have to go alone.
Wow, I can't believe it.
Are you serious?
This trip is only for me and Dad.
Now that Dad isn't here,
I need to go alone
with no one else.
That's that for today.
Every year this time,
Geu-ru went on a picnic with his dad.
A picnic? Where did they go?
Beats me.
If you're worried that much,
why don't you follow him?
I wish I could,
but I can't get away
from my mom today, so…
So?
-You should follow him.
-Me?
See you later.
Sure, see you.
Have fun.
A guardian always puts
their ward's safety first.
-Remember?
-What now?
I don't want to!
I'm not going. What's with you?
Never get distracted
nor get caught.
Come on.
-Go!
-Shoot.
Transferring.
Right.
How much? Here.
Transferring.
What the…?
So it's really a picnic, after all.
Why is he just watching?
No way.
Is he going to check all the rides here?
It's 1,800 won.
What is he buying?
Thank you.
No.
Let me do it.
-No way.
-Come on.
Let me do it!
What's with you?
You shouldn't leave the water running
in public places.
Water is public property.
What?
What did this loser say just now?
Who are you to try to teach us?
No smoking is allowed on the premises,
and minors shouldn't smoke.
Smoking harms your health.
It causes lung, larynx and oral cancer,
heart disease, stroke,
and sexual dysfunction.
What's your freaking deal?
Are you a robot?
What's wrong with your tone?
Maybe an AI robot from a movie?
He might be a machine
covered with human skin.
Hey, let's strip him down.
Wow, hold on. It gets fucking fun.
Give me your cigarette.
No, you shouldn't. This is wrong!
Dad!
-Don't move!
-Dad!
-He's looking for his daddy.
Why not your mommy?
Don't do this!
-Stay still.
-Please don't.
This is wrong!
-Don't do this. Please stop.
-Stay still, shit.
-The police. Freeze!
-Did someone call?
Bottom skate…
-Gosh, it reeks of cigarettes.
-…Chordata, Animalia.
-Its cartilage in…
-Are you okay?
Its head and pectoral fin…
No police after us?
Shit.
You've been told it's a smoking-free zone.
Gosh, who the heck are you?
What's up with you?
Fuck!
Shit!
Give me all your cigarettes.
Ten slaps for each you're hiding.
The boy in the bathroom
is not a robot. He's a genius.
He's ten times smarter
than all of your brains put together.
He's also older than you.
You should respect him.
Understand?
What did he say to you?
About the diseases you get from smoking.
He taught you, right? Say them.
Lung cancer!
It's lung cancer, sir.
Larynx cancer and oral cancer.
What else?
Already forgot?
-Will some beating help you remember?
-Sexual…
Sexual dysfunction.
That's right.
Keep smoking if you want.
We can say it's a way to protect the earth
not to have your kids in the world
who will take after you.
Aw.
Hooray!
Uncle!
What are you doing here? Why are you here?
-Did you follow me?
-Me?
No. I came here to have fun.
What? Am I not allowed to be here?
Is this place all yours?
-No, it's not.
-Hey!
The Space Fighter! Let's try that one!
Oh no!
No way! I can't ride in it!
You'll know whether you can or not
after you try it.
Have you tried it? It's not a big deal.
I haven't, and I won't!
I can't!
Frankly speaking,
I haven't either.
Let's go!
No way! No!
That's right. It's going up!
Doesn't it feel good?
Feel the wind.
Wow!
Come on.
Geu-ru, just once.
Open your eyes for just a second.
Please just for a second.
How is it?
Isn't it awesome?
Yes!
This is the last ride.
We have to get on it.
Another? Why don't we just go home?
No.
This day has to end with me and Dad
riding on the merry-go-round.
All right, let's go home now.
You go home, Uncle.
What? You're not coming?
I got things to do alone.
What? Can I go with you?
No, you can't.
I'm going by myself from here.
Don't follow me, Uncle.
Okay, then.
I'm hanging out here longer.
All right, see you at home.
Ungrateful brat.
I kept you company all day long.
You might get in trouble again
if you're alone.
I'm wasting my precious time.
CHICKEN
Yes, it's about time to eat.
Man, I'm starving.
Oh no.
Huh?
What?
He's having pizza after chicken?
Oh boy.
A Chinese restaurant? Now?
Is he filming mukbang or what?
Unbelievable.
Is he bulimic?
CHINESE RESTAURANT
Oh man!
Where is that food fighter going now?
Where are we?
YEAR 1994
DO NOT CROSS THE DANGEROUS TRACKS
Ta-da!
Wow!
-Did you make a wish?
-I forgot!
Come on. Close your eyes and make a wish.
I don't know what to wish for first.
You can wish
for what you want for your birthday.
I have tons! Can I wish for everything?
Sure, why not?
What do you want to do?
Well, my first wish is
to go to an amusement park
and try every single ride there.
Every ride in the park?
Yes, and I want to have chicken and pizza.
Well, and also…
Another food after that?
We have to have jajangmyeon too.
You want to eat them all in one day?
Yes, we can't leave anything out.
-Is that all?
-Far from it.
I need to get a birthday gift.
Okay, let's go over this.
You'll go to a park
and eat all those foods. Now a gift too?
Without getting a gift,
it's just a picnic, not a birthday.
Got it.
So, what kind of gift
would you like to have?
Let go.
Jeong-u gave it to me.
It's my birthday gift!
Nobody is happy
with a cockroach like you being born.
Give it to me.
-Let go, you brat!
-Stop!
-Please stop.
-Shit.
Your mom is dead now.
Why are you still here? Get out.
Get out!
What about Sang-gu?
He's my fucking son. Beat it now!
Get lost, you punk!
I said, get lost!
Jeong-u, don't go.
-I'll be back for you shortly.
-Hey!
-Take me with you!
-Out!
-Sang-gu!
-Jeong-u!
-Get lost, you punk!
CONDOLENCES
Drink this.
ONE YEAR LATER
Jeong-u.
Dad is dead.
-I know.
-They say I'm going to an orphanage.
No, you aren't.
I won't let you.
Really?
Sneak out with things you need
the night after tomorrow, okay?
Hide at the station.
I'll come and get you.
Until I come,
never get caught by anyone. Okay?
Don't worry.
It's the night after tomorrow.
June 29th.
Don't forget.
You shouldn't either.
-I won't. It's your birthday.
-Right.
It's my birthday!
I'll make your every wish
come true this year.
Really?
I promised you, remember?
SUIN STATION
He will come.
He promised to come.
My brother
never lies.
Jeong-u!
Where are you?
What's taking you so long?
What's all this?
-What are you doing?
-Oh!
Why did you follow me?
Why on earth are you here?
I came here every year with Dad.
Dad
made wishes like this.
And I'm making wishes on his behalf.
Wishes?
For what?
He made wishes for someone he loved
to be healthy and happy.
Unbelievable.
What the fuck?
Screwing me even now?
I don't care for this shit!
He forgot something more important.
But now I should thank him
for remembering this shit?
Don't put on a fucking show now!
Damn it.
Uncle.
Jeong-u.
Where are you?
Where?
SAFETY FIRST, DO NOT ENTER
Why couldn't you make it?
Why didn't you come?
I waited and waited.
I was really scared.
Why?
Dad said he felt guilty toward someone
because he couldn't keep his promise.
I waited for him three days.
A ten-year-old orphan waited three days
because he trusted his brother.
But he didn't come.
My brother who I admired the most…
abandoned me.
When were you supposed to meet?
In 1995.
June 29th!
Dad had a big scar on his back.
He got it from a big accident he was in.
An accident?
So that means
because he was involved in a big accident,
he couldn't make it?
Is it supposed to be his excuse?
Gosh, that's so freaking lame.
June 29th, 1995.
Sampoong Department Store
in Seocho-dong, Seoul
suddenly collapsed
due to structural failure,
which resulted in over 1,000 casualties.
They were employee or guests.
The fifth floor showed signs of collapse
in the morning of the disaster,
but they decided to stay open
while fixing the problems.
At 5:52 p.m.,
the entire building collapsed
in 20 seconds, making a pillar of dust.
The damage estimates were 270 billion won.
A total of casualties included 501 deaths,
six disappearances, and 937 injured.
It was the biggest casualties
since the Korean War.
A video tape containing footage
of the scene seven minutes
after Sampoong Department Store collapsed
has been disclosed.
Screams of those trying to escape
and cries for help
filled the entire footage.
Yoon Yeong-cheol has the story.
Imported luxury goods
were displayed here until yesterday,
but the entire building is now gone
as if it was bombed.
-Only debris…
-It's not a thatched hut.
-How could it collapse like that?
-Good grief.
I heard hundreds of people
are buried under the debris.
Dad said he was rescued
after being trapped for three days.
He was hospitalized for long
because he was badly hurt.
He met my mom in the same hospital.
Mom was always weak,
so she hated being in the hospital.
She said meeting Dad
was the only good thing happened there.
See? He was freaking lucky.
He was badly hurt. How was he lucky?
Because he didn't die
and met a girl like your mom,
he could turn his life around.
What does "turn his life around" mean?
It means his life has changed.
That's right.
Dad said his life changed
because of the disaster.
He said he decided
to be a firefighter since then.
4, HANEULSAN-RO 29-GIL
Hey.
Where are you going?
To put it in the cabinet in the storage.
The cabinet? What for?
There's no reason.
After this trip, we always put this there.
That's what Dad did.
Shit.
LOOKING FOR MY MISSING BROTHER
NAME: CHO SANG-GU
AGE: 10, BORN IN 1986
LAST SEE ON JUNE 30TH, 1995
So, what kind of gift
would you like to have?
Nike.
-Nike?
-Yes.
You mean the sneakers?
I want the real ones, not the fake ones.
They have to be
from a big department store in Seoul.
Okay, I'll get you those.
Really?
Here you are.
I'll make
your every wish come true this year.
SAMPOONG DEPARTMENT STORE
Sang-gu.
SANG-GU, HAPPY BIRTHDAY!!
JUNE 29TH, 1995
FROM YOUR BROTHER, WHO LOVES YOU
Sang-gu!
Sang-gu! It's me, your brother!
He passed away. I mean Mr. Han.
HAPPY 14TH BIRTHDAY, SANG-GU
JUNE 29TH, 1999 FROM JEONG-U
HAPPY 15TH BIRTHDAY, SANG-GU
JUNE 29TH, 2000 FROM JEONG-U
Jeong-u…
CERTIFICATION OF ADOPTION
NAME: HAN GEU-RU
"Adoption"?
Then Geu-ru was
adopted?
Subtitle translation by: Jean S Kim